Warren S. McCulloch Papers 1860s-1987 Mss.B.M139
American Philosophical Society
Warren S. McCulloch Papers
Circa 1935-1968
Mss.B.M139
American Philosophical Society
49.75 Linear feet
Correspondence and papers centering on McCulloch's study of the functional organization of the central nervous system and cybernetics. McCulloch (1898-1969) was a major figure in establishing the theoretical ground for modern computers and in "biological computer" studies during the 1960s. Other topics include the brain or neural studies, biological psychiatry, chemical warfare, space biology, and U.S. Army studies. His participation in the American Society of Cybernetics and the Josiah Macy Conferences is well documented, and there are numerous papers and notes on other conferences attended.
McCulloch, Warren S. (Warren Sturgis), b. 1898
Scope and Contents note
The McCulloch Papers Collection is comprised of 49.75 linear feet of the professional correspondence of the cyberneticist, psychologist, and philosopher, Warren Sturgis McCulloch. The collection centers on McCulloch's study of the functional organization of the central nervous system and its implications for cybernetic theory.
Reflecting McCulloch's original organization, the collection is divided into seven series
Correspondence, 1931-1968 (27 boxes; 13.5 linear feet)
Professional Papers, 1931-1992 (33 boxes; 16.5 linear feet)
Works by McCulloch, 1929-1974 (8.5 boxes; 4.25 linear feet)
Works by others, 1937-1979 (8 boxes; 4.0 linear feet)
Files of Rook McCulloch, 1866-1987, bulk 1960's-1970s (5 boxes; 2.5 linear feet)
Printed Material, 1941-1985 (1 box; .5 linear foot)
Photographs (25 boxes, 9.5 linear feet)
The collection is particularly strong for documenting McCulloch's role in the American Society of Cybernetics, conferences he attended (including the Macy conferences), and his pioneering research in computation and biological computers, as well as basic research in neural structure and function, biological psychiatry, chemical warfare, space biology, and research he conducted for the U.S. Army.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The McCulloch Papers were presented by Mrs. Rook Metzger McCulloch, February, 1970 (1970 686ms), and by gift in 1989.
Biographical/Historical note
A pioneer in cybernetics, neurology, and the development of the computer, Warren Sturgis McCulloch was born on November 16, 1898, in Orange, N.J. Beginning college at Haverford in 1916, McCulloch transferred to Yale in order to join the Officers' Training Program - an option not available at the Quaker school. After service in the Navy during the First World War, McCulloch completed his bachelors degree in philosophy and psychology at Yale (1921), and attended Columbia University for a masters in psychology (1923).
Having imbibed Descartes, Leibniz, and Kant, and fascinated with the relationship of physiology, perception, and thought, McCulloch entered the College of Physicians and Surgeons in New York to round out his background for understanding the role of the nervous system. After receiving his MD in 1927 and an internship at Bellevue Hospital, McCulloch held some routine professional appointments at Rockland State Hospital in Orangeburg, N.Y., from 1932 to 1934 - primarily to keep afloat during worst years of the Depression -- but in 1934, he returned to Yale as a Sterling Fellow (1935-1936) in the Laboratory for Neurophysiology, where he pursued research in neuroanatomy, tracing neural pathways in the brain. More important for the future of his career, McCulloch was placed in an environment in which he could cultivate his broader interest in philosophical issues relating to perception and thought and working toward his development of an "experimental epistemology." McCulloch remained at Yale as an instructor and assistant professor until 1941.
Although an important figure in the early development of computing, McCulloch's goal in research was as much to lay bare the foundations for how we think as it was to develop practical applications - or in other words, to develop an "experimental epistemology" with which to relate mind and brain. Perhaps the most significant work to emerge from this period of McCulloch's career was his landmark paper with Walter Pitts, "A Logical Calculus Immanent in Nervous Activity" ( Bulletin of Mathematical Biophysics 5 (1943): 115-133). The "Logical calculus" was an attempt to develop just that: a rigorous description of neural activity independent of resort to theories of a soul or mind. Together with McCulloch and Pitts' follow-up work, "How we know universals: The perception of auditory and visual forms" ( Bulletin of Mathematical Biophysics 9 (1947) 127-147), the "Logical calculus" provided a compact mathematical model for understanding neural relationships laying the groundwork for neural network theory and automata theory, and forming the ur-foundation of modern computation (through John Von Neumannn) and cybernetics.
McCulloch went from Yale to the University of Illinois College of Medicine (1941-1948) before joining the staff of the Electronics Research Laboratory at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology. Beginning in 1943, McCulloch chaired a series of ten eventful annual meetings funded by the Josiah Macy, Jr., Foundation. The Macy Conferences - attended by McCulloch, Pitts, Norbert Wiener, John Von Neumann, Margaret Mead, Gregory Bateson, Claude Shannon, Wolfgang Köhler, and Heinrich Klüver among others - were an effort to bring physiologists, anthropologists, and engineers to discuss signal processing, computation, and communication.
From the 1940s through the 1960s, McCulloch was actively involved in research in examining similarities between physical and biological systems and in theorizing a biological computer. He was instrumental in founding the American Society for Cybernetics, serving as its first president in 1967-1968. McCulloch died in Cambridge, Mass., in 1969.
American Society of Cybernetics; Automata theory; Biology--Research; Chemical warfare.; Computers; Cybernetics.; Information theory; Josiah Macy, Jr. Foundation; Military research; Neural computers; Neurology; Outer space; Perception--Physiological aspects; Psychology
- Series I. Correspondence, 1931-1968; 13.5 lin. feet (Box 1-28)
  Scope and Contents note
  Professional correspondence and other materials, including notes and printed materials. The series includes slightly over 0.5 linear feet of materials relating to the Josiah Macy Conferences.Additional correspondence is located in Series II, arranged by subject.
  - Abbott, John A., 1949-1968; 30 items
  - Abbott Laboratories, 1947-1948; 2 items
  - Abood, L. G., 1962; 1 item
  - Abrams, Arnold, 1969; 3 items
  - Academy of Psychosomatic Medicine, 1958; 1 item
  - ACE Engineering and Machine Co., Inc., 1955; 1 item
  - Acta Biotheoretica, 1955-1956; 4 items
  - Adamson, V. T., 1952-1953; 2 items
  - Addison-Wesley Publishing Co., 1963-1966; 10 items
  - Adelson, Marvin, 1958-1964; 13 items
  - Adler, Mortimer J., 1967; 1 item
  - Adley, Ross, 1960-1964; 9 items
  - Adrian, Edgar Douglas, 1947-1966; 3 items
  - Advances in Cybernetics and Information Science, 1962; 1 item
  - Aerospace Corporation, 1961; 2 items
  - Aerospace Medical Association Directory, 1968; 1 item
  - Agalides, Eugene, 1963; 2 items
  - Agricultural and Veterinary Chemicals, 1960; 2 items
  - Agron, Michael, 1947; 2 items
  - Aiken, Howard, 1953-1957; 2 items
  - Aikman, A. R., 1959; 1 item
  - Ainsworth, W. A., 1964; 1 item
  - Airesearch Manufacturing Co., 1959-1964; 4 items
  - Air Force Office of Scientific Research, 1965; 1 item
  - Albert, Mrs. Aurice V., 1957; 1 item
  - Alden, Carlos C., Jr., 1951; 8 items
  - Alden, Payne Services Inc., 1953; 1 item
  - Aldrich, C. Knight, 1947-1949; 2 items
  - Aldrich, Tony, 1963; 2 items
  - Alexander, E. J., 1953; 4 items
  - Alexander, John, 1953; 2 items
  - Alexander, Leo, 1959; 2 items
  - Allan, Mary, 1964; 4 items
  - Allen, Raymond B., 1942-1948; 30 items
  - Allen, William R., 1949-1958; 8 items
  - Allis, William P., 1962; 1 item
  - Allport, Floyd H., 1953; 4 items
  - Alonso, Jose Ramon, 1965; 1 item
  - Alpha Kappa Kappa. Xi Chapter, 1962; 2 items
  - Alpha Omega Alpha, 1945-1949; 3 items
  - Altschul, Sol, 1943-1966; 14 items
  - Alvi, Z. M., 1961; 1 item
  - Amador, L. V., 1950; 2 items
  - Amarel, Saul, 1966-1969; 8 items
  - Amassian, Valio, n.d.; 1 item
  - Amberson, William R., 1947; 3 items
  - American Airlines, n.d.; 1 item
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1949-1962; 37 item
  - American Civil Liberties Union, 1949; 3 items
  - American Forum for Socialist Education, 1957; 1 item
  - American Foundation for the Blind, Inc., 1959-1961; 6 items
  - American Geriatirics Society, 1967; 1 item
  - American Heart Association, Inc., 1953; 1 item
  - American Institute for Research, 1961; 2 items
  - American Institute of Architects. S. Atlanta District, 1957; 1 item
  - American Institute of Ultrasonics in Medicine, 1955; 1 item
  - American Journal of Psychology, 1951-1952; 3 items
  - American Journal of Psychotherapy, 1961; 2 items
  - American Lectures in Living Chemistry, 1961; 2 items
  - American Mathematical Society, 1962-1968; 2 items
  - American Men of Medicine, 1950-1960; 5 items
  - American Museum of Natural History, 1946; 5 items
  - American Neurological Association, 1967; 1 item
  - American Optometric Association, 1951; 18 items
  - American Psychiatric Association, 1956; 1 item
  - American Psychosomatic Society, 1950-1952; 3 items
  - American Physiological Society, 1954-1960; 2 items
  - American Scientist, 1964; 3 items
  - American Society for Cybernetics, 1968-1969; 31 item
  - American Society of Heating and Ventilating Engineers, 1951; 8 items
  - American Statistical Association, 1961; 2 items
  - Ames, Adelbert, III, 1951; 4 items
  - Ames, Edward, 1959-1966; 6 items
  - Ames, Gene K., 1967; 3 items
  - Amlinger, P. R., 1962-1966; 5 items
  - Anano, B. K., 1951; 3 items
  - Andermann, Karl, 1963-1966; 7 items
  - Anderson, Donald K., 1952; 2 items
  - Andrew, Alexander Miller, 1953-1966; 49 items
  - Andy, Orlando, 1950; 1 item
  - Angelus, Alex, 1959; 2 items
  - Angyan, Andre John, 1957-1966; 75 items
  - Animal Welfare Institute, 1951; 1 item
  - Annual Review of Physiology, 1947-1948; 11 item
  - Anthropoid Ape Research Foundation, Inc., 1946; 1 item
  - Appleman, Walter, 1957-1960; 7 items
  - Apter, Julia T., 1947-1967; 5 items
  - Arbib, Michael A., 1961-1969; 50 items
  - Architectural Forum, 1956; 1 item
  - Archives of Neurology and Psychiatry, 1948; 1 item
  - Arden, Geoffrey, 1963; 2 items
  - Argonne National Laboratory, 1951; 6 items
  - Aring, Charles D., 1940-1947; 9 items
  - Armsey, James W., 1947; 1 item
  - Arnett, Vitold, 1947-1950; 7 items
  - Arnold, John E., 1954; 1 item
  - Arnoult, Malcolm D., 1955; 1 item
  - Artigas, José Antonio de, 1954; 1 item
  - Asenjo, Alfonso, 1949; 2 items
  - Ashby, W. Ross, 1952-1963; 13 items
  - Association for the Advancement of Psychotherapy, 1949; 4 items
  - Astrom, Karl-Erik, 1950; 1 item
  - Atkinson, W. J., 1948-1968; 3 items
  - Atlanta Journal, 1961; 5 items
  - Auerbach, Isaac L., 1963; 1 item
  - Auger, Raymond N., 1955; 4 items
  - Aurilio, Giuseppe, n.d.; 3 items
  - Austin, G. M., 1949; 5 items
  - Autonetics, 1965; 1 item
  - Avakian, Emik A., 1955; 1 item
  - Aviv, David Gordon, 1955; 1 item
  - Babkin, B. P., 1949; 1 item
  - Bach, L. M. N., 1949-1957; 7 items
  - Bach-y-Rita, Paul, 1968; 2 items
  - Bagchi, B. K., 1960; 21 item
  - Bailey, Percival, 1952-1964; 31 item
  - Bailey, Percival to J. G. Dusser de Barenne, 1949; 2 items
  - Baker, Mrs. Della E., 1955; 1 item
  - Balabanian, Norman, 1955; 1 item
  - Balas, Egon, 1966-1967; 18 items
  - Ballou, J. W., 1949; 1 item
  - Balser, Benjamin H., 1949-1963; 7 items
  - Balz, Albert G. A., 1954; 2 items
  - Balz, George, 1948; 4 items
  - Bangs, Jack L., 1947; 2 items
  - Barbeau, André, 1962; 2 items
  - Barbour, William J., 1950; 3 items
  - Bard, Philip, 1947-1954; 14 items
  - Bareiss, E. H., 1960-1961; 6 items
  - Bar-Hillel, Maya, 1965; 3 items
  - Bar-Hillel, Yehoshua, 1954; 3 items
  - Barnard, John W., 1947-1952; 8 items
  - Barnett, Robert C., 1953; 2 items
  - Barrera, S. E., 1940-1942; 4 items
  - Barrett, Elliott P., 1947-1963; 12 items
  - Barrett, Eric, 1950; 1 item
  - Bartlett, James H., 1949; 3 items
  - Barron, E. S. Guzman, 1948; 3 items
  - Bartolo, Baldassare, 1958; 1 item
  - Bassi, Achille, 1967; 1 item
  - Bastin, E. W., 1963-1964; 4 items
  - Batchelor, James H., 1962; 2 items
  - Batcher, Ralph R., 1949; 3 items
  - Bates, J. A. V., 1949-1950; 3 items
  - Bateson, Cathy, 1969; 1 item
  - Bateson, Gregory, 1954-1963; 7 items
  - Battersby, Albert, 1963-1968; 12 items
  - Baudoin, A., 1950; 1 item
  - Bay, Alfred Paul, 1949-1952; 12 items
  - Bazett, H. C., 1949; 1 item
  - The Beacon Press, 1956; ?? items
  - Beals, Harold L., 1950; 2 items
  - Beatty, Denis C., 1963; 1 item
  - Becker, Hal C., 1953; 4 items
  - Beckwith, R. W., 1961; 2 items
  - Becvár, Jiri, 1965; 1 item
  - Bedrosian, Alvin D., 1969; 2 items
  - Beer, Stafford, 1959-1965; 20 items
  - Beeson, Paul B., 1961-1962; 3 items
  - Bell, George H., 1950; 5 items
  - Bell Aerosystems Co., 1961; 2 items
  - Bell Telephone Laboratories, Inc., 1949-1954; 9 items
  - Bellman, Richard, 1950-1967; 21 item
  - Bender, Lauretta, 1955; 1 item
  - Bender, Morris B., 1947-1961; 9 items
  - Ben-Haim, N., 1964; 2 items
  - W. A. Benjamin, Inc., 1967; 2 items
  - Bennett, A. E., 1953; 2 items
  - Bennett, Frederick D., 1947; 3 items
  - Bennett, Leslie L., 1954; 3 items
  - Bennett, H. Stanley, 1965-1966; 5 items
  - Berenden, Herman J. C., 1959-1962; 50 items
  - Berger, F. M., 1954; 1 item
  - Bergman, Stefan, 1952; 7 items
  - Berkeley, Edmund C., 1947-1951; 3 items
  - Berry, John M., 1951-1954; 8 items
  - Bertelsen, William R., 1949; 2 items
  - Bessey, Otto A., 1948; 1 item
  - Best, C. H., 1947; 2 items
  - Beurle, R. L., 1966; 1 item
  - Beutler, Frederick J., 1958; 3 items
  - Beuvle, R. L., 1947-1949; 4 items
  - Bevans, H. Gordon, 1967; 4 items
  - Benzuly, Harold J., 1957; 1 item
  - Bickers, Donald, 1948-1952; 26 items
  - Bickford, Reginald, 1948; 1 item
  - Bigelow, Julian H., 1949-1956; 7 items
  - Binkley, Francis, 1949; 2 items
  - Bios Laboratories, Inc., 1952; 2 items
  - Bird, Robert B., 1951; 1 item
  - Bishop, George, 1941-1947; 13 items
  - Blanke, Francis G., 1941-1945; 4 items
  - Blatnik, Jim, 1967; 1 item
  - Blum, Baruch, 1965-1968; 1 item
  - Blum, Edward H., 1963-1964; 5 items
  - Blum, Harry, 1966; 4 items
  - Blum, Jay, 1966-1967; 2 items
  - Blum, Manuel, 1959-1968; 12 items
  - Boba, Antonio, 1939; 4 items
  - Boder, David P., 1963; 3 items
  - Boehm, George A. W., 1963; 3 items
  - Bogoch, Samuel, 1956; 1 item
  - Bogue, J. Yule, 1931-1958; 6 items
  - Bohnert, Herbert G., 1969; 1 item
  - Bok, S. T., 1958-1959; 6 items
  - Bond, Earl D., 1952; 1 item
  - Bongaarts, John, 1969; 1 item
  - Bonhoeffer, K. F., 1919; 1 item
  - Bonner, J. T., 1965; 2 items
  - Booker, Richard, 1944-1945; 2 items
  - Borenszatajn, David L., 1968; 10 items
  - Borger, Robert, 1966; 7 items
  - Bostock, John, 1953; 1 item
  - Boston Society of Psychiatry and Neurology, 1954; 1 item
  - Botterell, E. H., 1950; 1 item
  - Bottomley, Alastair H., 1965; 3 items
  - Bouman, Maarten, 1967; 3 items
  - Bourguignon, Georges, 1948; 1 item
  - Bowden, Ruth E. M., 1950; 3 items
  - Bowen, Charles R., 1962; 1 item
  - Bower, Anthony D., 1960-1961; 3 items
  - Bowie, Carol C., 1947; 2 items
  - Bowker, John D., 1957; 2 items
  - Bowles, Chester, 1962; 1 item
  - Bowman, Carolyn R., 1964; 3 items
  - Bowman, John R., 1950-1960; 12 items
  - Brace, Edward R., 1961-1969; 14 items
  - Braceland, Francis, 1947-1960; 17 items
  - Bradley, Tom, 1949; 1 item
  - Brain, Alfred E., 1963; 2 items
  - Brain, Russell, 1958; 1 item
  - Brain Research Foundation, 1962-1964; 8 items
  - Braines, S. N., 1963; 3 items
  - Braitenberg, Valentino, 1958-1967; 16 items
  - Brand, Howard, 1951; 2 items
  - Brandman, Harry, 1949; 3 items
  - Bradner, William M., 1951; 2 items
  - Brannin, Richard S., 1959; 2 items
  - Brauman, John, 1955; 3 items
  - Braverman, Maxwell H., 1966; 1 item
  - Brazier, Mary A. B., 1947-1951; 10 items
  - George Braziller, Inc., 1965; 3 items
  - Breedveld, Max P., 1964; 5 items
  - Bremer, F., 1949-1962; 6 items
  - Brickner, Richard M., 1957-1959; 5 items
  - Brief, Jean, 1963; 5 items
  - Bristol Mental Hospitals, 1949; 1 item
  - British Broadcasting Corporation, 1966; 4 items
  - British Journal for the Philosophy of Science, 1954; 1 item
  - Brodal, A., 1959; 2 items
  - Brodersen, Rolf, 1948; 1 item
  - Brodey, Kim, 1966; 4 items
  - Brodey, Warren M., 1964-1965; 36 items
  - Brookhart, John M., 1947; 1 item
  - Brookhaven National Laboratory -- Symposium on Homeostatic Mechanisms, 1957-1959; 3 items
  - Brooks, Vernon B., 1948-1968; 13 items
  - Brosin, Henry W., 1949-1959; 47 items
  - Brown, J. H. U., 1967; 1 item
  - Brown, Joel, 1969; 2 items
  - Brown, Warren T., 1947; 5 items
  - Bruce, Ruth, 1965-1967; 2 items
  - Brücke, E. Th. von, 1940; 2 items
  - Brues, Austin M., 1962; 5 items
  - De Bruin, Peter P., 1949; 1 item
  - Bruner, Jerome S., 1963; 2 items
  - Brunia G. H. M., 1962-1964; 6 items
  - Brunswik, Egon, 1950-1954; 13 items
  - Brust, Albert, 1950; 2 items
  - Buchthal, F., 1959; 2 items
  - Buck, Dudley, A., 1954; 1 item
  - Bucy, Paul C., 1943-1949; 8 items
  - Budreau, Alan, 1958; 2 items
  - Bueding, Ernest, 1947; 2 items
  - Buffalo Ophthalmologic Club, 1956; 1 item
  - Buhler, Karl, 1949; 1 item
  - Bulloch, Theodore H., 1948-1963; 9 items
  - Bunch, M. E., 1948; 4 items
  - Burchard, John E., 1961; 2 items
  - Burckluchler, Henry, 1948-1950; 3 items
  - Bures, J., 1960; 2 items
  - Burger, H. C., 1958-1959; 5 items
  - Burhoe, Ralph W., 1954-1968; 5 items
  - Burian, Hermann M., 1968; 1 item
  - Burke, Thomas Edward, 1968; 38 items
  - Burke, Thomas Edward, 1968-1969; 11 item
  - Burks, Arthur W., 1960-1965; 4 items
  - Buser, P., n.d.; 1 item
  - Bush, E. L., 1949; 1 item
  - Butcher, Charles, 1965-1966; 3 items
  - Butsch, Leonard M., 1962-1963; 5 items
  - Bye, Lilian, 1961-1962; 4 items
  - Cahen, Raymond L., 1950; 2 items
  - Caianiello, E. R., 1962-1969; 16 items
  - Cairns, Hugh, 1949-1952; 6 items
  - Calhamer, Allan B., 1960; 1 item
  - Calhoun, John B., 1950-1965; 4 items
  - Callahan, Eleanor M. (Mrs. John D), 1967; 1 item
  - Callahan, Leslie Griffin, Jr., 1962-1966; 11 item
  - Callaway, Enoch, 1952-1964; 4 items
  - Cambridge University Press, 1963-1967; 24 items
  - Cammarata, Joseph A., 1958; 2 items
  - Campbell, Berry, 1948-1951; 11 item
  - Campbell, James H., 1965; 1 item
  - Canney, Heyward E., Jr., 1965-1966; 7 items
  - Cannon, Walter Bradford, 1944-1949; 2 items
  - Cappon, D., 1952; 2 items
  - Cardot, Claude, 1951; 1 item
  - Carlson. Earl R., 1949-1950; 11 item
  - Carlson, Esther Jane Jensen, 1948-1949; 4 items
  - Carlson, Helen B. [Also] Correlation of Hypoglycemia with fatigue and anxiety, 1951; 5 items
  - Carman, Alexander R., Jr., 1953; 1 item
  - Carmichael, Hugh T., 1947; 2 items
  - Carmichael, Leonard, 1947; 2 items
  - Carnap, Rudolf, 1955-1956; 4 items
  - Carr, J. Gordon, 1954; 1 item
  - Carrigan, Patricia M., 1959; 2 items
  - Carriol, Jacques H., 1950; 1 item
  - Carter, John R. C., 1959; 2 items
  - Case Institute of Technology, 1963-1966; 5 items
  - Caskey, Paul H., 1950-1968; 20 items
  - Castillo, Jose del, 1958; 1 item
  - Castro, Gustavo de, 1967; 2 items
  - Caws, Peter J., 1966; 2 items
  - Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences, 1957; 1 item
  - Cetis Euratom, 1961; 1 item
  - Chamberlin, Gary, 1967; 1 item
  - Chang, Hsiang-Tung, 1947; 1 item
  - Chao, Y. R.
  - Chapanis, Alphonse, 1958; 1 item
  - Chappell, Matthew N., 1952-1953; 6 items
  - Chapuis, Alfred, 1948-1949; 4 items
  - Chen, Graham, 1948-1957; 4 items
  - Cherry, Colin, 1956-1960; 4 items
  - Chicago Academy of Science, 1958-1965; 9 items
  - Chicago Heart Association, 1948; 1 item
  - Chinn, Herman I., n.d.; 1 item
  - Choynowski, Mieczyslaw, 1951-1959; 7 items
  - Christensen, Haaken, 1959; 1 item
  - Christmas Cards, 1965-1967; 5 items
  - Churchman, C. West, 1952; 1 item
  - Chusid, Joseph G., 1966; 2 items
  - Cichon J. Valentine, n.d.; 2 items
  - Clark, Edward C., 1947; 2 items
  - Clark, John, 1966; 2 items
  - Clark, William G., 1943; 2 items
  - Clark, W. E. LeGros, to J. G. Dusser de Barenne, 1940; 3 items
  - Clark University. Department of Psychology, 1961-1964; 2 items
  - Clarke, Arthur C., 1959; 2 items
  - Clemente, Carmine D., 1966; 1 item
  - Clough, S. DeWitt, 1950; 2 items
  - Clowes, M. B., 1961-1962; 5 items
  - Clynes, Manfred E., 1960-1967; 14 items
  - Coales, John F., 1953-1955; 4 items
  - Cobb, Stanley, 1949; 16 items
  - Cohen, Jerome, 1956-1964; 1 item
  - Colby, K. M., 1955; 1 item
  - Cole, Kenneth S., 1950; 2 items
  - Collaham, Griff, 1967; 1 item
  - Computer Graphics and Architecture Conference, 1968; 5 items
  - Computing Reviews, 1966; 1 item
  - Conant, Lawrence Wickes, 1964-1968; 9 items
  - Conant, Spicer V., 1965; 1 item
  - Concerning "Odor", 1949-1959; 10 items
  - Concerning "Monkeys", 1946; 3 items
  - Conrad, George P., II, 1954; 2 items
  - "Conscientious objectors", 1942-1943; 6 items
  - Cook, George B., 1962; 4 items
  - Cooke, P[acirc]uline, 1953-1968; 21 item
  - Coombs, William C., 1970; 2 items
  - Cooper, Irving S., 1947; 1 item
  - Copp, Belton A., 1962; 2 items
  - Coppock, Harold, 1948; 1 item
  - Corbiere, Henri, 1959; 2 items
  - Corliss, Edith L. R., 1968; 1 item
  - Cornell University. Center for Applied Mathematics, 1968; 2 items
  - Corner, George Washington, 1949; 2 items
  - Corning, William, 1966; 1 item
  - Corriol, Jacques H., n.d.; 1 item
  - Corsellis, J. A. N., 1958; 1 item
  - Cote, A. J., 1960; 2 items
  - Coulney, G. Souléman, 1953; 2 items
  - Coulter, Norman A., Jr., 1951; 2 items
  - Council on Library Resources, Inc., 1965; 3 items
  - Cowan, Jack D., 1963-1968; 79 items
  - Craig, Edward J., 1955; 1 item
  - Craik, Kenneth, 1960-1963; 12 items
  - Crane, Edward V., 1955; 4 items
  - Crane, Hewitt D., 1960-1961; 2 items
  - Crespi-Reghizzi, S., 1967; 1 item
  - Cretcher, Leonard H., 1950; 7 items
  - Crosby, Elizabeth, 1947-1961; 10 items
  - Crossman, John S., 1954-1955; 4 items
  - Crouch, C. L., 1956; 2 items
  - Crouch, Dick, 1947; 5 items
  - Crowlie, A. C., 1953; 1 item
  - Crozier, William J., 1953; 6 items
  - Cuevas-Novelo, Alberto, 1956; 2 items
  - Culver, William H., 1957-1958; 8 items
  - Cunningham, A. W. B., 1958; 2 items
  - Current Trends, 1958; 1 item
  - Cybernetics Research Institute, Inc., 1969; 5 items
  - Dage Electric Company, 1951; 1 item
  - Dalton, Jack, 1949; 1 item
  - Daly, John A., 1963; 1 item
  - Danielli, Jim, 1967; 1 item
  - Darby, Jeannette L., 1950; 2 items
  - Darling, Harry F., 1964; 3 items
  - Das, N. N., 1950; 2 items
  - Davidson, James A., 1953-1958; 5 items
  - Davidson, James Romanes, 1950-1968; 17 items
  - Davidson, Robert A., 1967; 2 items
  - Davis, George, 1948; 1 item
  - Davis, Hallowell, 1939-1953; 6 items
  - Davis, Maxine, 1949; 4 items
  - Davis, Ruth M., 1965; 1 item
  - Davis, Ted, 1963; 2 items
  - Davis, William O., to William Kilmer, 1964-1965; 2 items
  - Dawson, George, 1953; 1 item
  - Dean, Bill, 1947; 1 item
  - de Koven, Don, 1963-1969; 31 item
  - Debreau, Gerard, 1952; 1 item
  - Delbruck, Max, 1949; 1 item
  - Dell, Paul C., 1947-1952; 15 items
  - DeMaios, Joseph, 1958; 4 items
  - Denier van der Gon, J., 1962; 2 items
  - Dennis, Wayne, 1950-1951; 18 items
  - Denny-Brown, Derek, 1950; 3 items
  - Derjaguin, Boris V., 1968; 1 item
  - Desmedt, J. E., 1959-1963; 4 items
  - Detroit Dianetic Associates, 1951; 9 items